Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series II: Children's Literature, undated, 1947-1989
  - Unidentified color dummies, small, undated (Box 15:, Folder 587)
  - Unidentified dummies, undated (Box 15:, Folder 588)
  - Unidentified children's collections, contents lists, undated (Box 15:, Folder 589)
  - Unidentified children's collection, undated
    - A, "Guest Pages", undated (Box 15:, Folder 590)
    - B, undated (Box 15:, Folder 591)
    - C, undated (Box 15:, Folder 592)
    - D, undated (Box 15:, Folder 592a)
  - Unidentified children's poetry collections
    - A [tss and mss], undated (Box 15:, Folder 593)
    - B [tss and mss], undated (Box 15:)
    - C, "Book for Babies" [tss], undated (Box 15:)
    - D, "A Book of Poems for Children" [contents list], undated (Box 15:, Folder 596)
    - E, Babystitters [contents list], undated (Box 16:, Folder 597)
    - F Poems for a Boy [tss], undated (Box 16:, Folder 598)
    - G [contents list and sketch], undated (Box 16:, Folder 599)
    - H, undated (Box 16:, Folder 600)
    - I, undated (Box 16:, Folder 601)
    - J, undated (Box 16:, Folder 602)
    - K, undated (Box 16:, Folder 603)
    - L, undated (Box 16:, Folder 604)
    - M, undated (Box 16:, Folder 605)
    - N, undated (Box 16:, Folder 605a)
    - O, undated (Box 16:, Folder 605b)
    - P [tss and copies], undated (Box 16:, Folder 605c)
    - "Charlotte's collection," oversize [contents list], undated (Box 17:, Folder 644)
  - A Very Special House
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 16:, Folder 606)
    - Dummy and copy, undated (Box 16:, Folder 607)
  - What a Fine Day For
    - Partial manuscripts, undated (Box 16:, Folder 608)
    - Illustrated partial manuscript, undated (Box 16:, Folder 609)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 16:, Folder 610)
    - "Original version" [tss], undated (Box 16:, Folder 611)
    - Final typescript, 1966 April (Box 16:)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 16:, Folder 613)
    - Illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 16:, Folder 614)
    - Partial dummies, undated (Box 16:, Folder 615)
    - Undated dummies (Box 16:, Folder 616)
    - Dummy, 1966 December (Box 16:, Folder 617)
    - Dummy, 1967 June (Box 16:, Folder 618)
    - Cover envelope, undated (Box 16:, Folder 619)
  - ["When I Grow Up"]
    - Cover envelope, undated (Box 16:, Folder 620)
    - Notes, undated (Box 16:, Folder 621)
    - Undated manuscripts (Box 16:, Folder 622)
    - Undated typescripts (Box 16:, Folder 623)
    - Dated manuscripts and typescripts, 1961 January - September (Box 16:, Folder 624)
    - Sketch, undated (Box 16:, Folder 625)
    - Dummy fragments, undated (Box 16:, Folder 626)
  - Woodchuck (unppublished) [dummy and copy], undated (Box 16:, Folder 627)
  - Work with Judy [tss, mss, and drawings], undated (Box 16:, Folder 628)
  - Young Collection (unpublished), c. 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 628a)
  - "Zoo Party" (unpublished) [tss and sketches], undated (Box 16:, Folder 628b)
- Series III: Prose, undated, ca. 1938-1979
  - "The Amber Room"
    - Summary [tss], undated (Box 19:, Folder 666)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 667)
  - Anthropology Book
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 19:, Folder 668)
    - Notes, undated (Box 19:, Folder 669)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 670)
    - Undated typescripts (Box 19:, Folder 671)
    - Typescripts, 1948-1950 (Box 19:, Folder 672)
    - Sample layout page, undated (Box 19:, Folder 673)
    - Partial dummies, undated (Box 19:, Folder 674)
  - "Child with the Sun on a String" [tss and copies], undated (Box 19:, Folder 675)
  - "The Dream"
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 19:, Folder 676)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 677)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 678)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 19:, Folder 679)
  - Dream journals [mss, tss, and copies], 1953-1957 (Box 19:, Folder 680)
  - Elizabeth Hears Our Story of the Flood
    - Manuscript fragment, undated (Box 19:, Folder 681)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 19:, Folder 682)
    - Later typescript copy, annotated, undated (Box 19:, Folder 683)
    - Typescript copy with Krauss's annotations, undated (Box 19:, Folder 684)
    - Typescript with annotatoins by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 19:, Folder 685)
  - The Flying Schlemiel/Black Aspirin [tss], undated (Box 19:, Folder 686)
  - "Happy Breakfasts"
    - Typescript copy, undated (Box 19:, Folder 687)
    - "Basil and I" [copy], undated (Box 19:, Folder 688)
    - "Susan and I" [copy], undated (Box 19:, Folder 689)
  - "The House" [tss], ca. 1938-1939 (Box 19:, Folder 690)
  - Intensive writing journal, 1979 October (Box 20:, Folder 691)
  - The Last of the Mad Waffles
    - Untitled short story with comments [2 copies], undated (Box 20:, Folder 692)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 20:, Folder 693)
    - Typescript copy, undated (Box 20:, Folder 694)
  - "My Habits" [tss], undated (Box 20:, Folder 694a)
  - "One Foot in a Butter Dish,", undated (Box 20:, Folder 694b)
  - "Prose Sestina" [tss and copy], undated (Box 20:, Folder 695)
  - "Reb" [tss and sketch], undated (Box 20:, Folder 695a)
  - "Statement on Poetics" [tss], undated (Box 20:, Folder 696)
  - Untitled autobiographical story
    - Manuscript pages, undated (Box 20:, Folder 697)
    - Typescript A, annotated, undated (Box 20:, Folder 698)
    - typescript B, undated (Box 20:, Folder 699)
  - Untitled book [tss and copy], undated (Box 20:, Folder 700)
  - Untitled short stories [tss], undated (Box 20:, Folder 701)
  - "Where Am I Going?" [annotated tss and copy], undated (Box 20:, Folder 702)
- Series IV: Notebooks, undated, 1954-1964
  - Small Notebooks
    - Children's literature, undated (Box 21:, Folder 703)
    - A Hole is to Dig and others, undated (Box 21:, Folder 704)
    - Poetry assignments and A Bouquet of Littles, undated (Box 21:, Folder 705)
    - Poetry assignments and notes, undated (Box 21:, Folder 706)
    - Poetry assignments and notes, undated (Box 21:, Folder 707)
    - Poetry notes and work with children, undated (Box 21:, Folder 708)
    - Work with children, undated (Box 21:, Folder 709)
    - Poetry assignments and notes, 1959-60 (Box 21:, Folder 710)
  - Medium Notebooks
    - Diet journal, undated (Box 21:, Folder 711)
    - The Happy Egg, undated (Box 21:, Folder 712)
    - Poetry assignments and ideas, undated (Box 21:, Folder 713)
    - Work with children and A Hole is to Dig, undated (Box 21:, Folder 714)
    - "Special," children's literature ideas, undated (Box 21:, Folder 715)
    - Work with children, undated (Box 21:, Folder 716)
    - Nina Rowland Wallace, 1954 (Box 21:, Folder 717)
    - Poetry assignments and notes, 1960 (Box 21:, Folder 718)
    - Poetry assignments, 1961 (Box 21:, Folder 719)
    - ,Poetry work and assignments, 1963-1964 (Box 21:, Folder 720)
  - Large Notebooks
    - Italian, undated (Box 21:, Folder 721)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 21:, Folder 722)
  - Sketch notepad, undated (Box 21:, Folder 722a)
- Series V: Crockett Johnson Materials, undated, 1952-1986
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1964-1975
    - Correspondence to Johnson
      - A - B, 1964-1975 (Box 22:, Folder 723)
      - C - D, 1968-1975 (Box 22:, Folder 724)
      - Children, 1986 (Box 22:, Folder 725)
      - Cricket, 1974 July - August (Box 22:, Folder 726)
      - Dover Publications, 1972 February - March (Box 22:, Folder 727)
      - F, 1973 (Box 22:, Folder 728)
      - G, 1969-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 729)
      - Goodman, Calvin J., 1971-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 730)
      - H, 1960-1975 (Box 22:, Folder 731)
      - Harper and Brothers, Harper and Row, 1957-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 732)
      - Japan UNI Agency, 1972-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 733)
      - L, 1960-1972 (Box 22:, Folder 734)
      - M, 1963-1978 (Box 22:, Folder 735)
      - Museum of Art, Science, and Industry, 1969 November - December (Box 22:, Folder 736)
      - O - P, 1965-1971 (Box 22:, Folder 737)
      - S, 1947-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 738)
      - U - W, 1960-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 739)
      - Unidentified correspondents, 1961-1973 (Box 22:, Folder 740)
    - Correspondence from Johnson, 1974 (Box 22:, Folder 741)
  - Subseries B: Children's Literature, undated, 1952-1986
    - Barnaby and Mr. O'Malley, treatement for screenplay, 1960? (Box 22:, Folder 742)
    - Barnaby books
      - Jackets, undated (Box 22:, Folder 743)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1986 (Box 22:, Folder 744)
    - Barnaby comic strip, newspaper clippings, 1985 June (Box 22:, Folder 745)
    - Bibliography of Johnson's books, 1975 October (Box 22:, Folder 746)
    - Harold and the Purple Crayon
      - Paste-up and copy, ca. 1955 (Box 22:, Folder 747)
      - Jacket paste-up, ca. 1955 (Box 28:, Folder 859)
    - Harold and the Purple Crayon (musical), post-card announcement, undated (Box 22:, Folder 748)
    - Harold and the Purple Crayon (video), correspondence, 1986 (Box 22:, Folder 749)
    - Harold and the Purple Crayon (video), Storyboards [incomplete], 1986 (Box 22:, Folder 750)
    - Harold at the North Pole
      - Paste-up and copy, ca. 1957-58 (Box 22:, Folder 751)
      - Jacket blurb galley, ca. 1957-58 (Box 22:, Folder 752)
    - Harold's ABC
      - Paste-up and copy, ca. 1963 (Box 23:, Folder 753)
      - Dust-jacket paste-up, undated (Box 28:, Folder 850)
    - Harold's Circus
      - Paste-ups and copies, undated (Box 23:, Folder 754)
      - Oversize paste-ups, undated (Box 28:, Folder 851)
    - Harold's Fairy Tale
      - Paste-up and copy, ca. 1956 (Box 23:, Folder 755)
      - Jacket blurb, ca. 1956 (Box 23:, Folder 756)
      - Jacket tracings and mock-up, ca. 1955 (Box 28:, Folder 852)
    - Harold's Trip to the Sky
      - Paste-up, ca. 1957 (Box 23:, Folder 757)
      - Jacket blurb galley, ca. 1957 (Box 28:, Folder 853)
    - Unidentified broadside with paste-up, undated (Box 23:, Folder 758)
    - Unidentified sketches by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 23:, Folder 759)
    - Who's Upside Down?, copy of corrected proofs, c. 1952 (Box 23:, Folder 760)
    - Unidentified overlay, undated (Box 28:, Folder 854)
  - Subseries C: Other Artwork, undated, 1953-1985
    - Artwork, article off-prints, 1971-1975 (Box 24:, Folder 761)
    - Artwork, exhibition brochures, undated (Box 24:, Folder 762)
    - Artwork, newspaper clippings, 1985 October (Box 24:, Folder 763)
    - Brun Mael yearbook, with illustrations by Johnson, 1953 (Box 24:, Folder 764)
    - "Budgetism" by William H. White Jr., with illustrations by Johnson, 1956 May (Box 28:, Folder 848)
    - Film Designers, Inc., promotional portfolio, undated (Box 28:, Folder 857)
  - Subseries D: Official Records, 1952-1970
    - Mattress design
      - Correspondence, 1952-1958 (Box 24:, Folder 765)
      - Patent, 1955 October (Box 24:, Folder 766)
      - Schematics, 1955 October (Box 24:, Folder 767)
      - Large schematic, ca. 1955 (Box 28:, Folder 855)
      - Photo negatives, ca. 1955 (Box 28:, Folder 856)
    - Voter registration form, 1970 (Box 24:, Folder 768)
- Series VI: Manuscripts Submitted for Review, undated, 1946-1989
  - Bartlett, Jennifer, Cleopatra I-IV, undated (Box 25:, Folder 769)
  - Boyle, Kay, "The Double Cage,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 770)
  - Broughton, James, "The Princess of the Water Level,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 771)
  - Chase, Naomi Feigelson
    - C.V., after 1979 (Box 25:, Folder 772)
    - Listening for Water, undated (Box 25:, Folder 773)
    - Poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 774)
  - Converse, Elizabeth, undated
    - "Cara and Caledonia,", 1985 December (Box 25:, Folder 775)
    - C.V., after 1984 (Box 25:, Folder 776)
    - "One One Day,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 777)
    - Shaman Lab, undated (Box 25:, Folder 778)
  - Dobbie, Joan, Sometimes Poems by Jaymee and Amber, March 1989 (Box 25:, Folder 779)
  - Eastman, Jeff, "Exercises for the End,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 780)
  - Fessenden, Anne, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 781)
  - Fox, R., poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 781a)
  - Fraser, Kathleen, "Blues for Sylvia,", 1965 June (Box 25:, Folder 782)
  - Gordon, Corrinne, "The Far-Out Fairy,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 783)
  - Good, Ruth, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 783a)
  - Grantz, Linda Hana, untitled work, ca. 1973 November (Box 25:, Folder 784)
  - Green, Jonathan, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 784a)
  - Grenadier, Del
    - "A Japanese Fairy Tale,", 1986 December (Box 25:, Folder 785)
    - "Mean Streets and Malls,", 1987 (Box 25:, Folder 786)
    - "Mirrors,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 787)
  - Hausman, Gerald
    - "The Little Girl of Pine Knoll,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 788)
    - "Oh, Owls,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 789)
  - Heinrich, Peggy, "The Magic Pendulum,", 1988 (Box 25:, Folder 790)
  - Hirsh, Lolly, "The Breeders,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 791)
  - Inglese, Phyllis
    - "Back in Tampa at Daddy's House", undated (Box 25:, Folder 791a)
    - "Great Guana Cay,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 791b)
  - Klapport, Peter, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 792)
  - Klein, Binnie, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 793)
  - Kobler, Evelyn, "Failure,", 1971 September (Box 25:, Folder 794)
  - Koch, Kathleen, and Koch, Kenneth, Andrew Goes to Rome, undated (Box 25:, Folder 795)
  - Krauss, Janet, poems, ca. 1982 (Box 25:, Folder 796)
  - Lawrence, Vivian, "The Year of the Native American,", 1974 February (Box 25:, Folder 797)
  - Lembke, J., poems, 1967-1973 (Box 25:, Folder 798)
  - List, Shelley, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 799)
  - Lund, Doris, "Taking Care of Harry,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 800)
  - Malanga, Jerry, poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 800a)
  - Markopoulous, Gregory, Twice a Man [exerpt], undated (Box 25:, Folder 801)
  - Michael, Elizabeth
    - "Foraging,", undated (Box 25:, Folder 802)
    - Poems, undated (Box 25:, Folder 803)
  - Neville, Helen, poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 804)
  - Orgel, Doris
    - "My Mother Listens to People's Hearts" [two versions], ca. 1982 November (Box 26:, Folder 805)
    - "The Old Steeple-Clock,", ca. 1973 (Box 26:, Folder 806)
    - "Steeple-Gockel,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 807)
    - "Vanishing Cream,", 1981 August (Box 26:, Folder 808)
    - Why? Who? How? When? and Other Verses, undated (Box 26:, Folder 809)
  - Poetry Classmates' Poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 810)
  - Ramington, John, poems, 1977 (Box 26:, Folder 811)
  - Reeves, Carol, "A Crowd, a Host" [incomplete], undated (Box 26:, Folder 812)
  - Reynolds, Tim, poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 812a)
  - Rosen, H., poems, 1986 (Box 26:, Folder 813)
  - Sesar, Carl, poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 814)
  - Sessler, Harvey M., poems, 1987 (Box 26:, Folder 815)
  - Shapiro, David, When Will the Bluebird, 1962 (Box 26:, Folder 816)
  - Shaw, Dale
    - "The Loom,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 817)
    - "Welcome to Unitania,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 817a)
  - Sherman, Barbara Swanson, Adventures in the Alphabet, undated (Box 26:, Folder 818)
  - Shifrin, Susan, poems, October, 1962 (Box 26:, Folder 819)
  - Starr, Frances, Blueprints, undated (Box 26:, Folder 820)
  - Stoetzer, Rona, "Berlin, May 1947,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 821)
  - Students' poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 822)
  - Thomas, Bill
    - Booklets, ca. 1968 October (Box 26:, Folder 823)
    - The Whole Nevermind[oversize], undated (Box 28:, Folder 847)
    - The Whole Nevermind, undated (Box 26:, Folder 824)
  - Unidentified Authors
    - "The Duel,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 825)
    - "The Ladykillers" [copy 1], undated (Box 26:, Folder 826)
    - "The Ladykillers" [copy 2], undated (Box 26:, Folder 827)
    - In What America?, undated (Box 26:, Folder 828)
    - "Oedipus and Eve,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 829)
    - "A Room Full,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 830)
    - Poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 831)
    - Short prose pieces, undated (Box 26:, Folder 832)
    - "The Young Words,", undated (Box 26:, Folder 833)
  - Vaugh, James, poems, undated (Box 26:, Folder 834)
  - Walsh, Lewis, "The Suicide Rates,", ca. 1964 February (Box 26:, Folder 835)
  - Wolfenstein, Martha, "The Impact of a Children's Story on Mothers and Children,", ca. 1946 (Box 26:, Folder 836)
- Series VII: Financial and Other Records, 1967-1990
  - Dividend income statement, Maryland National Bank, 1973 January (Box 27:, Folder 837)
  - Employee search bill and copy, 1990 May (Box 27:, Folder 838)
  - Word processor receipt, 1987 September (Box 27:, Folder 839)
  - Medical receipts, 1984 April - 1990 July (Box 27:, Folder 840)
  - Random House contract, unsigned, undated (Box 27:, Folder 840a)
  - Royalty Statents, Harper and Row, 1967 June - December (Box 27:, Folder 841)
  - Royalty Statents, Harper and Row, 1971 January - June (Box 27:, Folder 842)
  - Royalty Statents, Harper and Row, 1971 July - December (Box 27:, Folder 843)
  - Royalty Statents, Harper and Row, 1972 January - June (Box 27:, Folder 844)
  - Savings worksheet, 1986 February (Box 27:, Folder 845)
  - Voter registration approval, 1981 October (Box 27:, Folder 846)
- Series VIII: Poetry, undated, 1958-1988
  [Poetry is filed alphabetically by title. Those poems published in one of Ruth Krauss's books are filed alphabetically under the book in which they were first published, with the exceptions of "This Breast," "If Only," and "When I Walk I Change the Earth," which were published later as stand-alone books.
  Titles are problematic in Krauss's poetry. Many poems are untitled. Untitled poems, including the numerous different poems named "Song" or "Poem," are generally filed under "Untitled and unidentified poems" if they were not published in any of Krauss's books. Untitled poems found in books are alphabetized under the first line. Krauss gives different names to the same poem, or, occasionally, the same name to different poems.]
  - undated (Box 29:)
  - "2 End of World,", undated (Box 29:, Folder 859)
  - "4 Tomatoes in 3 Cans,", undated (Box 29:, Folder 860)
  - 7 Poems Involving Word-Play(unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 861)
  - "16 Ways of Taking off from Liliyflower" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 862)
  - "20 Sun and Moon Collages" [sketches], undated (Box 29:, Folder 863)
  - "Adaptation Using the End of a Lorca Poem" [tss and copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 864)
  - "Adele Cavity a Poem" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 865)
  - "The African Computer Poems" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 866)
  - "After George Herbert" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 867)
  - "After Lorca" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 868)
  - "After Yeats" [copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 869)
  - "Ah!" [tss and mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 870)
  - "Ah-ha-a" [mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 871)
  - "Ah We Could Not" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 872)
  - "Ahoi! My Poem" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 873)
  - "All" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 874)
  - "All Our Wings and No Sky" [tss and copies], undated (Box 29:, Folder 875)
  - "Alone With" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 876)
  - "Always Hear Times Winged" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 877)
  - "America Week" [tss and copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 878)
  - "An" [tss and copies], undated (Box 29:, Folder 879)
  - Andy Auto Body (unpublished collection) [tss, mss, and copies], undated (Box 29:, Folder 880)
  - "Apologia" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 881)
  - "Apologies to Someone" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 882)
  - "Apologies to Stevens" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 883)
  - "Apology to Stephens" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 884)
  - "Artaud Reverdy et Moi" / "Artaud Reverdy and Myself" [tss, mss, and copies], undated (Box 29:, Folder 885)
  - "As Soon As the Idea of Deluge was Reassisted" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 886)
  - "Astrocontamination" [tss and copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 887)
  - "At Sperry's Cafe" / "Trip to Sperry's" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 888)
  - "Avocado Drunk Boat" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 889)
  - "Baby St. George and the Dragon" [tss, copy, layout sketch], undated (Box 29:, Folder 890)
  - "Bad Poem" [copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 891)
  - The Bar Mitzvah Poems of Seth Jacobson
    - Drafts, undated (Box 29:, Folder 892)
    - Later typescripts and copies, undated (Box 29:, Folder 893)
  - "Bathtub Ballet" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 894)
  - A Beautiful Day
    - Fliers, undated (Box 29:, Folder 895)
    - Programs and tickets, undated (Box 29:, Folder 896)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 29:, Folder 897)
  - "Because" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 898)
  - "Because I am Me" [tss and mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 899)
  - "Begin" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 900)
  - "The Bells are Ringing" [tss and copies], undated (Box 29:, Folder 901)
  - The Berkshire Anthology, newspaper clipping, 1972 July (Box 29:, Folder 902)
  - "Bigger and Better Words" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 903)
  - "Bird Birthday" [tss and mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 904)
  - "The Birth of Calculus" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 905)
  - "Black Blues" [tss and mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 906)
  - "Black Days" [mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 907)
  - The Blue Papers (unpublished) [tss and mss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 908)
  - "Blue Skies" [copy], undated (Box 29:, Folder 909)
  - "The Blues" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 910)
  - "Blues, Blues, Blues" [tss], undated (Box 29:, Folder 911)
  - "Body Heart Soul Mind Love" [tss and copies], undated (Box 30:, Folder 912)
  - "A Book for Taking Pills" [copy], undated (Box 30:, Folder 913)
  - Book for Two Voices (unpublished), contents list [mss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 914)
  - Book of Macdowell [tss; This typescript may be incomplete.], undated (Box 30:, Folder 915)
  - "Book Review" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 916)
  - "A Boy, a Woman, and a Cake" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 917)
  - "The Boy on a Silver Horse" [copy], undated (Box 30:, Folder 918)
  - "The Boy Who Remodeled the World" [mss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 919)
  - "Bricks" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 920)
  - "The Broken Bowl of the Broken Sky" [tss and copies], undated (Box 30:, Folder 921)
  - "Building Bigger and Better Worlds" [tss and mss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 922)
  - "The Burning Bush" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 923)
  - "Burning Bush" (prose poem) [tss and copies], undated (Box 30:, Folder 924)
  - "The Butterfly" [tss and copies], undated (Box 30:, Folder 925)
  - "A Button" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 926)
  - "Button, Button" [tss, copies, notes, sketches], undated (Box 30:, Folder 927)
  - "Button Poems" [tss and mss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 928)
  - "By the Sea" [mss and tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 929)
  - "Cancion" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 930)
  - The Cantilever Rainbow
    - Notes, undated (Box 30:, Folder 931)
    - The Sun Book (early manuscript), undated (Box 30:, Folder 932)
    - Title List, undated (Box 30:, Folder 933)
    - "Dream", undated
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 934)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 935)
      - Spanish Translation [See also New Collection.], undated (Box 30:, Folder 936)
    - "Duet"
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 937)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 938)
      - Layout dummies, undated (Box 30:, Folder 939)
    - ["Experiments"] [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 940)
    - "He or Himself or" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 941)
    - "It is Caught in that Water-Pitcher" [tss and copies], undated (Box 30:, Folder 942)
    - "It is Following You Right Now" [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 943)
    - "Name-Calling at the Sun"
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 944)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 945)
    - "Ode"
      - Notes, undated (Box 30:, Folder 946)
      - Early version [tss], undated (Box 30:, Folder 947)
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 30:, Folder 948)
      - Dated manuscripts, 1964-1967 (Box 30:, Folder 949)
      - Typescripts and copies, undated (Box 30:, Folder 950)